hey guys sh the side welcome to concept
and coding uh in jpa till now we have
seen about what is jdbc and in the jpa
architecture and first level caching
second level caching right and many more
things so today let's go further and see
more annotations and how the mapping of
the entity and tables happens so this is
the first thing we have to configure in
our application. property
spring. jpa do hybernate
doddl auto what does it do it's a
configuration which tell hibernate
regarding how to create and manage the
DB schema so we have to add it
into application. properties file okay
so
here here if you see in the application
do properties we have to add this
value so in the application. properties
we have to add this value so we can
provide certain values like none update
validate create create draw okay
depending upon our use case we can
Define any one of them so the first one
is the
none it do not create a schema do not
update a schema do not delete a schema
actually it does nothing and it is good
for production so for production I would
always recommend using use this only
nothing else because in production we do
write DB script and then give to DBA DBA
will run we have a plan for roll back
everything okay so always use none in
the
production while you are doing
development update is a good choice like
here like it will create a schema if it
is not there it will update the schema
okay if it is already there let's say
you are there are already four columns
now in your entity there are five
columns so one new column so it will
update it will add new but it will not
delete anything okay does update but
without deleting any existing data or
schema good for development
environment the third one is validate
again it do not create do not update do
not delete any data or schema it just
validate or do a matching between the
entity
and the DB schema right whatever the
entities which you have created in your
classes and it will match that both are
matching or not if it find any
discrepancy it will throw an
exception then fourth one is create it
will create a schema update a schema and
yes it deletes the schema also so drop
and recreate the schema during
application startup so whenever you
start your application right so for
first it will drop drop all the data all
the schema and then creates a new schema
fresh similarly there is something
called create hyphen drop it is very
very similar to create but only thing
is when you start an application it will
create the schema but when you shut down
the application it will drop the schema
okay so create what it does is during
application startup itself it first drop
and then recreate here what it will do
is during a startup it just do only
create and during application shutdown
it just do only
drop okay you
can test all these things by keeping the
value here let's say for say I am using
Create hyphen drop okay so now when I
start an
application so what it
does it just create table
when I stop the application now I'm
stopping it so during a stop it drops it
okay similarly if I use
create you know what will happen during
create only it will first drop and then
create okay so first it will drop table
and then
create okay so we can easily validate uh
using this and we can choose depending
upon our choice but I have already told
you in production always go for none and
development uh update is
sufficient okay before proceeding
further let me also tell you about
difference between DB and esema I'm not
sure I am uh I'm pretty much sure many
of you are already aware of this it's uh
nothing related with Java it's a DB
concept so there are two part right DB
and schema a DB can have multiple
schemas right SCH schema 1 SCH schema 2
SCH schema 3 SCH schema 4 right so you
can in this schema you can have logical
grouping of tables table one table two
Table Three let's say table four table 5
Table Six belongs to schema 2 similarly
you can logical group the tables into
different
schemas so how these are helpful right
generally in organization where they
have only one DB but there are multiple
teams so they can create different
schemas for each team and they can
provide a proper ownership to the
different team to each schema so they
can utilize Only One DB but inside 1 DB
itself they can have multiple schema and
each schema ownership belongs to one
particular team you can say okay so they
can group their tables in a particular
schema and they own the ownership for
that one if you don't provide any schema
then you are ultimately adding your
table directly here okay so
that is also right but uh if if if you
can say that in your company
each team has their own DB then this is
okay right my team has my own DB so that
is okay I don't have to create a schema
but there are a scenario like if One DB
is shared by multiple teams then schemas
comes into the picture Okay so that's
where uh the terms schema we are seeing
it uh
right okay now let's start the first
thing we have to start with atate table
annotation so if you remember from our
previous video while creating an entity
I was using at theate entity annotation
because this will tell that jpa has to
look for this class and treat this class
as an entity means it is equivalent to a
table in a
DB okay and each stance of this entity
considered as a row in that table but we
were not using at the table annotation
till yet why because it's an optional
field if you don't Define it hnet will
create the table name based on the
entity name so my entity name is user
detail so maybe hibernate internally
will create user uncore details so
generally S2 will create all capital
letter and follow the camel case
whenever there is a camel case it put
under
underscore but you can specifically
mention Yourself by at theate table
itself give the name so when you will
check your DB you will see that this
name whatever you have defined here that
will come
okay so if you see inside this table
annotation this is the name which is
used to provide what a specific name you
wanted to give to your table okay then
there is something called scheme
I already told you what a schema is
right so if you want your table to be
part of a particular schema then provide
it
here okay if you don't want to be part
of any schema don't add it okay so now
here if you see
that I want to part of any schema so I
put schema and provided the name
onboarding so there is one schema so
remember that hibernate not
automatically create this schema we have
to create the schema so here in this
case how we can create the schema is see
this one so in application. properties
there is something called spring.
datasource DOL where we have provided
what is the DB okay there we have to
provide like
this in it equals to now we have to
create a schema create a schema if not
exist whatever the name of the schema
you want to give if you want to create
more schema you can another at like
create schema you can add as many
schemas you like this wanted okay so we
can create a schema
first schemas are not if you just write
a schema here but not right here
hibernate not will not automatically
create a schema it will say that schema
not found so we first have to create the
schema like this okay then we can tell
that okay this table should belongs to
this schema if you don't want to be part
of this or any schema don't write it
okay so now what would happen is if you
see there is one schema already created
okay and now this user details goes
here user details goes
here so there I I I also have one more
entity which is like order
details right and I didn't use any
schema so it directly goes under the DB
it is not under part of any
schema
okay so and I already told you what is
schema it's nothing but a logical
grouping of tables okay you can provide
some permission that only these these
these teams or Engineers will have
permission for this schema nobody can
access it apart from those rules okay so
that's why if you want you can use
schema provide like this on in the
condition that you have defined the
schema or created the schema before
itself so then you have third one here
in this uh table attribute is unique
constraints so like this you can add in
a table we have multiple columns which
you want it to be
unique okay column one column two column
3 let's say you want certain columns to
be unique
then you can Define like this so unique
constraints equals to right and it
accept The annotation unique constant
annotation column name whatever the
column name uh which you have provided
so single column unique constraint so I
might have a column name phone now I
made it unique constraint so all the
values inside it would be unique
similarly you can also so club together
two columns together composite unique
constraint so they both together should
be unique name and email together should
be
unique okay so you can give like this
column names equals to this one at
theate unique
constraint okay so this is a table level
so in in a particular table whatever the
columns you have you can provide this
unique constraint like this
okay so now here if you see that this is
my Fields columns and I have put a
constraint unique constraint on phone
and name and email so if you check the
schema here I will see that
uh here I can see that phone
number is is constraint added UK is uh
uni key right unique constraint
similarly this both email and name they
both are same key right because I have
used it together so together they form a
unique
constraint okay so like this you can add
more values so table has one more
attribute which we can use is index
so here if you go
here so we can add indexes like this you
can use indexes equals to
and any number of index you want to
create on a Columns of a table so now
let's say that I want to create so these
are my column I want to create an index
on phone okay so I have put the name
name of an index in the column list
which is an string I give like phone
this is the column name so on
phone this index is created okay on
phone similarly I created another index
okay I gave this name and on the
composite column on this two columns I
have added it so here column list if you
go inside this index annotation right
column list is then a string so it
accept like this okay so name comma
comma
separated so comma separated column we
can provide so name comma email so index
on composite columns okay so here if you
see
that the same name which is on name and
email okay so now it's been
indexed now we have to see add theate
column annotation very simple again it's
an optional field if not defined jpa
will add added with default values okay
so now let's say that I have created
entity and I provided the table name
user details okay and U now these are
all the fields even though here and here
I haven't provideed at the rate column
and for this I am providing at theate
column jpa also add annotation for this
for this but with default values but
here I am not using default values I'm
setting mine so at theate column
name even though it's name but in the DB
I want name full underscore name okay so
if you see that in DB what name comes
full underscore name not just
name okay so that is one thing another
thing is if there is only one column you
want to make it unique you can also do
it here unique equals to True similarly
as we saw above right we have unique
constraint so there also you can use it
on a single column or if you don't want
to use at a table level you can also use
at a column level so you can use like
unique equals to true if you want to
make it nullable true or false that it
value can be null or not you can provide
like it can be empty or not so by
this attribute you can set it and even
the length of the field you can
determine if you don't provide this
value
jpa internally set the default values
like email it will considered as capital
hnet generally uh for S2 everything uh
turned out to be a capital uh letters
right and uh phone it changed to phone
but with default values unique might be
false nullable might be false length
might be let's say 50 okay so some
default values it will
set okay
now these are the two another important
annotation we have to be aware at theate
ID annotation and at theate generated
value
annotation so
now what at theate ID is used for it is
used to Mark the field as a primary
key okay every table should have one
unique value which is used to uniquely
identify each each record that is known
as primary key and in an entity and in
an entity right the class we can use at
theate ID
annotation to Mark the field as primary
key so each entity can have only one
primary key so each entity at theate
entity can can have only one primary
key and only one field can be with atate
ID I can't do like hey this is also
atate ID email is also atate ID no only
one field we can mark it at the rate
ID but now your question might come hey
what about the composite primary key in
composite key there can be more than one
column then how to do that because we
have put a constraint that at theate ID
can only be used on one field
but what about the composite primary key
how it can be
handled so there are two ways to
handle composite primary key One is
using at the rate embeddable and at the
rate embedded ID another is with at
theate ID class and at theate ID
annotation okay so we'll see this but
there are certain rules which we have to
follow
so it must be a public class so we
create a new class where we provide all
the fields which are composite primary
key that class should be a public
class I will provide you a reason also
it must implement the serializable
interface right that public class need
to implement the serializable interface
it should have one no argument
Constructor and must override the equal
and hash code
method okay so there is a proper
reasoning why this rule need to be
followed and we'll see that first let's
see with this at theate ID class and at
theate ID annotation how composite
primary key can be defined primary key
it's already clear right we have already
seen example here I am using primary key
at the rate ID okay so ID is my primary
key
PK but for composite key CK how to do it
so first approach let's say that using
at theate ID class and at theate ID
annotation now let's say that this is my
table okay I have created an entity this
is the table name which I have given
these are the field and I want these two
columns to Mark as a composite key name
and address together they uniquely
identify a
row okay so now here in this how we can
do is I can't put at the ID here atate
ID here no it won't
work so we am first approach we are
using it at theate ID class so see this
one so I have created one
class public class the first rule I have
created a public class let's say user
details CK composite key and I have
implement the serializable second
rule okay we Define all the fields which
I wanted to consider as a composite key
so I want name and address right so I
put name and address
here the third rule it should have one
no argument Constructor even if you
don't write it generally uh default
Constructor is always added if you don't
have any argument Constructor but for uh
rules to follow just to say I mentioned
here that this is the third rule which
says that there should be one no
argument Constructor should be
present and the fourth rule says that we
should overwrite the equal and the hash
code method so I have overrided so I
have name and address right so equals I
have said that if
object whatever the this object and the
object which is coming if both are equal
directly return true no problem the
other use case is that if the object
which is coming and this objects are
different then return FSE
if the instance instance is same it is
still a user detail CK then I can
compare this individual value also if
values also matching name and address is
also matching then I would say that yes
they are equal okay either so in short
either both the objects this
object the one in the parameter and the
one this object if both are same then
return true if both objects are
different but of same type then we
individually compare all the values like
name address if they both are equal then
we say that yes the both objects are
equal and similarly hash code I am using
objects. hash and passing this list of
values and internally it will create
some hash code and
return okay so this is the fourth like
you have to uh provide your
own functionality for the equals and
hash code I will tell you all also
y now once this class is
created what we have to do is in your
entity class where you have defined your
table there we have to use this atate ID
class
annotation and this is the class user
details ck. class okay like this we have
to provide this
annotation and whatever the
fields for which you have determined a
composite key you have put at theate ID
over here so remember that this ID is
not equivalent to that primary key no
now you have annotated your class with
adate ID class right now whatever the
adate ID you will put on the field those
together would be considered as
composite key and those should be
present into this class
here okay now here if you see the schema
uh you will see that index name it
created
on address and name this address and
name it created a composite key
together okay so this is one way but now
your question can come is say why it has
to implement
serializable why we have to implement
equal and hash code so this is my
understanding why we need to override
equal and hash code so you from the
previous video you know that jpa
internally maintain first level caching
and also it we can Implement second
level caching and in both it uses
hashmap and generally we have key and
value right in hashmap the key is
generally the primary key so now here in
this case the key is our composite key
right and it's a separate class more
than one field so how the equal and the
hash code should work
that you will guide
right for your scenario okay only if
name is equal I I can consider that yes
two objects are equal but in some
scenario no all the field exactly should
match then I would say it is equal it
determines like your business uh
functionality okay so that is one of the
reason because internally we use uh
hashmap for lot of features jpa like for
first level caching so it relies on this
key which is nothing but a primary key
so for that hash map it required equal
and hash
code okay another you can say that then
why we need to implement
serializable and why we when when we
were using primary key like at theate
only entity and let's say at theate ID
primary key let's say long
ID we were not implementing this class
uh Implement serializable right why then
for composite key I need to uh Implement
serializable that question can also come
so the my understanding is unlike single
primary key like a string long composite
key are custom classes
okay you are not just putting atate ID
over here not like one field a string or
long or something in the composite key
we are creating a separate
class okay that considered as a
composite key now we need to make sure
that this class should be like Ser in a
serializable format like in future if
required I should be able to serialize
this class okay so jpa need to make sure
that those classes should be properly
serializable and if you implement that
class uh class serializable that will
make sure that yes in future let's say
that uh during distributed caching
and over the network we have to pass
this object jpa should be able to
serialize this class
properly so this is the second approach
using embeddable and embedded ID
annotation the composite key so again I
am creating a new
class public class first rule second
rule implement the serializable third
rule have one no our Constructor fourth
rule uh I have equal and hash code
defined same everything same but only
thing is I have put atate edible here
one annotation here and in the entity
now I don't need adate ID class
something right no now in the entity I
can use adate embedded ID and provide
the class this this
class okay so I can provide the
reference of this class now this will
make sure that this would be added as a
primary key uh composite key so now when
the table get created for this entity
right here address name phone all comes
properly address name phone all comes
properly and even the address and
name address and name are indexed both
together okay so this is the second
approach using at theate embeddable and
at theate embedded ID for the composite
key how we can create
it and we have one more like a very
important part is at theate generated
value annotation so now we know how to
define primary
key yeah at the rate ID
annotation but we can also Define its
generation strategy too by default
primary key columns are not autofill
remember
that so let's say that I have put at the
rate ID long
ID now whenever you are trying to do
insert you have to provide like what id
because even though it's a primary key
right but it will not be like autofill
you have to provide like what id unique
value some unique value you have to
provide but with the help of atate
generated value
annotation you can transfer this
responsibility to hibernate
also okay so at theate generated value
only works with at theate ID annotation
only for single primary key not for the
composite one you remember like atate ID
class and that we can also use at theate
id id but those are different those are
not the primary key one those are
composite key ones so at theate
generated value Works only with at
theate ID annotation for single primary
key
one so what are the different types we
can give the first type is
identity so like this we can give so
here I have created at theate entity
class given a table name user undor
details I have this three field for the
long I have created atate ID it's a
primary key but I have put an at theate
generated value strategy I have given is
Generation type.
identity so this means that auto
increment it's an autoincrement field
so each insert will generate a new
value so here if you see that first time
I did an insert with this object this is
the response I got ID is created one
even though I haven't passed anything ID
one second time I hit it with some value
I got id2 even though I haven't passed
ID anything here okay internally it auto
increments id2 and if you check the DB
it will like this 1 2 3 4 like it will
goes
on okay and this is very very specific
to table
okay this is very important and many big
Industries also uses this generation
type do
sequence okay big companies use it in a
little bit different flavor I can tell
you but first understand this
one used to generate unique numbers
okay speed of the efficiency when we
catch sequence value more control than
identity we'll understand this three
points uh more better let's first see
this
query now let's say that if I am writing
a DB query you can create a sequence
like this hey create
sequence you can give some name whatever
you
want increment by 25 start with 100
maximum value is 9
999 so you can create a sequence let's
say that uh I have one sequence which is
named user scq this is the
name start value is let's say
100 increment I have tell is 25 and max
value of have tell is
9999 so now when anybody asks this that
hey give me the value let's say next 12
give me the next 12 so it will start
with 100 not with some one 2 three
whatever the start you have pointed then
again it say that hey give me next 12
then increment by 25 125 150 175 200
like this it will go till it reach Max
9999 after that we can tell what to do
okay whether we want I think a cycle or
no cycle means after that don't again go
to 100 okay or after that to stop it
okay so we can provide this also it has
feature that we can cache it can
generate
uh hiet can generate let's say 50 values
only in the one time itself it can ask
the sequence that hey generate 50 values
and give it to me and hbanet can cash it
in its memory so that every time it need
one unique value it don't have to ask
the sequence that hey give me give me
give me next Val
so you can save some DB
hit you can simply directly ask hey give
me 50 value give me 100 values it will
generate it and send it to you and hnet
can store it so it also has that
capability so how to define it into the
entity let's see that how to do that I
am creating a new entity
class at theate ID so I have this three
field and for this ID I want a sequence
generator like how we do it so how to do
that first let's create a sequence
generator so at theate sequence
generator is The annotation which we
have to
use this is the name first field name
is the unique name but for the jpa which
in the Java classes you can use
different entity you can use okay the
first is the name unique any name you
can provide and it can be used uh within
the classes itself
then second field is sequence name this
is the name which ultimately goes to the
DB in the DB what name you want for this
sequence so that will go or let's say
that in DB you have already created the
sequence yourself and now you want it to
attach to this sequence generator then
you can provide the sequence name so
from DB it will not create new it will
use that DB name one if it already has
if it don't have it will create
new initial value
from where it will
start allocation size this is like
hibernate is asking that hey uh generate
five values five unique values and give
it to me so now you can say that when
you have writing a direct SQL query you
have more control over max value you
have more control over like uh what is
the increment by 2550 or on so here at
theate sequence generator there are not
much field only this so 100 after that
it will increment by one 100 1 1002 1003
like this it will go okay but it provide
us the capability that you uh hiet can
tell in a single shot generate this five
unique values give it to me and it will
cash
it okay so this is first sequence
generator now we put at the rate
generated value now the strategy which
we are using is sequence and Generator
which we are using is this one
this okay so now the they both got
linked with
this so now when you start an
application right uh so
here first time I
hit what idea I got 100 not one because
I have told like what is the initial
value second time I hit I got one1
because here in the sequence generator
we don't have a capability to tell
increment so it's always increment by
one only and in DB it will go like
this okay so these I have already
explained you what is name sequence name
initial value allocation
size so here if you see allocation size
I have given five right here in this
one so now see this so I am hitting five
time insert so first time it did insert
100 second time 101 1002 103
104 right so 3 4 five insert happen no
DB call has been made okay after that
when sixth time I am doing
insert okay before that it make
one next value with the quence DB
sequence name okay hibernate will fetch
another five
values okay so that's where it says that
sequence helps in caching so that we can
cash
certain prefetch values unique values
and you can use it okay uh from the
cache you don't have to every time go
and check with the DB that he give me
one unique
value okay so that is also one of the
advantage of the sequence so here I can
show you here in the this one so let's
see
that generated value sequence let's
say So currently application is not uh
running so I am creating a sequence
generator name I am giving some
unique
unique um us user details anything this
is for
entity but in the DB I want name like
user undor SQ I want this name in the DB
for this
sequence okay and initial value I want
it to start with 200 and allocation size
I want three so in in one time it makes
a DB query three queries it will
generate okay and this and this ID I
will link it with this generator equals
to this
name okay so now they are link now I am
starting my
application so now my application got
started now let's
see so here if you see the one sequence
is
created what is the sequence name user
undor SQ right this is the name right
user unor SQ I have given this is the
name DB name initial value
is 200 and increment by three so
generally here this is wrong like
incremented is
one allocation size I have provided
three here in hnet allocation size means
in the three three chunk whenever any it
it will make a query for the
sequence it will get three IDs in return
and store
it okay now let's say that the first
time I am making a post call let's say
a so when I am hitting it it is started
with ID 200
100 okay so if we see the
log so first time it make a
query hey give me the because the insert
we are doing the insert for the first
time right so it will make One DB query
to take out the sequence from the DB
unique sequence and the allocation size
I have given three so means three IDs it
has got and stored it so then it
inserted it then I hit another two times
1 2 so now here if you see it does
insert does insert but it do not make
any query for the sequence to give any
value because it already has now the
fourth time I do here if you
see it makes one query select next value
from user _ sequence okay and then it do
does insert now again another two times
you won't see anything right so here if
you see another two times you don't see
anything and if you make now again you
will
see uh select query for the user
sequence okay
and you can ask me like hey sh what is
the advantage of sequence over identity
first thing I'll tell you that sequence
is very important what many companies
does is they have a separate very small
microservice which expose some API and
which many microservices are using it to
generate sequence generate sequence
generate sequence so one advantage we
already see that this sequence right it
is not tied up with very specific to a
table it is a total separate logic and
that's why it can be considered as a uh
separate microservice and it takes a
control and you can say that a
centralized we can have all the logic
which takes care of all the unique value
uh key generation and it helps or
fulfill all the different
microservices so we can have custom
logic one advantage of sequence over
identities we can have custom logic
sequence generation logic is independent
of table so multiple table can use it
right so even if you have 10
tables those can use it like so it can
helps to generate a unique number for
those 10 it's not very specific tied up
to a specific table in identity it is
very tied up like Auto increment of a
table so very tied
up range of IDs can be cached so we can
avoid hitting database each time a new
ID is required another is better
portability means identity is very DB
specific some DB Auto increment is
different maybe Oracle is different my
SQL is different postgress is different
how the auto auto increment
works and let's say that today you are
in Oracle and you wanted to move to my
SQL their Auto auto increment Works
totally different so portability brings
an issue but if you're using sequence
since you are taking the responsibility
what should be the start how much should
be increment what should be the end so
portability is like easy better
portability you can move from different
DB as the consistent Behavior you can
have into multiple
DBS okay because you have more
control so there is one more like
Generation type. table I will not
explain that because it hardly used in
the industry so there is like how how we
are using here at theate sequence
generator
right similarly there is something
called atate table
generator this annotation is used but
it's very Le less efficient why because
here a new table is created just for
let's say maintaining the
sequence okay it has one column let's
say sequence and it it keep on adding
you can say that let's say one column
one value it keep on incrementing and it
gives the value but a new table is
created and it's very less efficient you
know right why separate table is created
just for maintaining unique ID each time
ID is required select and update query
is executed first you make a select
query hey give me the well it will
return let's say this is the well and
second time you update it change from 1
to two now this is should be the next
value now you know that when a table is
involved a complexity comes when the
concurrency handling when multiple
operation is happening in parallel it
require lock unlock feature also which
can lead to Performance bottleneck now
let's say current value is for this
table scq is one now
two uh insert operation comes and they
both want what should be the next value
I can use for the primary key now they
goes to this table and since this table
we they have to put a lock right so one
have to put a lock consume it okay I
will use one and increment it to two so
that second one it can use
two okay but remember that in
sequence it's an atomic counter there is
no table there is no table involved it's
just a counter so it's much more
efficient and faster okay and DB is only
handling it that
counter okay so here now this Logics
comes to you in the table you as soon as
table comes you have to maintain it but
that DB internally handles sequence like
whatever the counter it has Atomic
counter it will handle like what one to
two like so even though concurrency
happen it makes sure that only one of
them uh all of them get the unique
value
okay so that's why I in 9 years I have
never seen that at theate table
generator is used but I can tell you
that this sequence is very very
used okay so in next part I will cover
all this relationship Association one to
one one to many and in then part seven
last part I will cover the custom
queries criteria queries pag generation
and sortings so only these two left and
hopefully I'll complete it as soon as
possible